

OAHIDUL ISLAM

Electrical & Electronic Engineering Student Robotics and Tech. Enthusiast

PROFILE

Hi there, I am Oahidul Islam. Recently, I completed my BSc. degree in Electrical & Electronic Engineering (Major in Wireless Communication Technology) from Daffodil International University (DIU). I am working on Machine Learning and Data Science. I am also doing Research Works. I am an ambitious and hardworking individual, with broad skills. Time management and team work is my strength. Furthermore, I am adept at handling multiple tasks on a daily basis competently and at work well under pressure. I use a creative approach to solve my problem.

CAREER OBJECTIVE

To work for the Corporation, especially in the Machine Learning/Telecommunication/Operations/Electronics Manufacturing/Robotics & Automation department were enormous opportunities for professional growth with increasing responsibilities.



01766551148





https://bit.ly/3Nbx3zW



Uttara Azampur, Sector:6, Road:15 Uttara, Dhaka-1230



https://bit.ly/45EMIVf

EXPERIENCE

ROBOTICS TRAINER & TEAM LEADER JAN 2020-Present

> MECHANICAL DESIGNER

JUN 2022-Present

TRAINER
DESIGNER
(CAD)
JUN 2022

TEAM APEX

TEAM OCTOPUS, FOR MORE INFORMATION WEB LINK https://bit.ly/3NcmEEj

GRABCAD CAMBRIDGE ROBOTICS 3D DESIGNER

WEB LINK https://grabcad.com/wahid-9

TRAINER (CAD)
3D ROBOTICS DESIGN

DAFFODIL INTERNATIONAL UNIVERSITY

EDUCATION

BSc in EEE STARTED IN JAN 2019-2023 BSc in ELECTRICAL AND ELECTRONIC ENGINEERING (Major in Wireless Communication) DAFFODIL INTERNATIONAL UNIVERSITY (DIU) CGPA: 3.97

CERTIFICATION

5G for Everyone

Qualcomm Wireless Academy Certificate: https://bit.ly/3IXiKN4

Introduction to Data, Signal, and Image Analysis

Vanderbilt University

Certificate: https://bit.ly/3NcrIIQ

Modeling and Design for Mechanical Engineers

Autodesk

Certificate: https://bit.ly/43laE9b

The Arduino Platform and C Programming University of California, Irvine

Certificate: https://bit.ly/3qrL093

Project Planning: Putting It All Together

Google

Certificate: https://bit.ly/3NconcL

Machine Learning with Python

IBM

Certificate: https://bit.ly/3qvoF5l

PROFESSIONAL SKILLS

ROBOTICS

C Programming

PCB Design

Antenna Design

Solidworks/Fushion360

Python

UI/UX design

TOOLS & TECHNOLOGIES

Arduino

MATLAB

Proteus

Microsoft Office suite

Adobe Products

Operating System

Machine Learning

INTERPERSONAL SKILLS

Leadership
Time Management
Team work
Problem Solving
Dependability
Analytical
Responsibility

ACHIEVEMENT

Champion

4IR Competition-2022

GrameenPhone & Cisco Networking Academy

1st Runner Up

Cyber Security Awareness Project Showcasing-2022

Cyber Security Center & Dept. of Computer Science & Engineering

Daffodil International University Details: https://bit.ly/3qo8tmG

1st Runner Up

Robot Nokshar Ashor-2021

Robotics LAB & Dept. of Software Engineering

Daffodil International University Details: https://bit.ly/45lrkJg

Academic Scholarship

6 times achieved 50% & 3 times 30% Scholarship based on CGPA result Daffodil International University

COMMUNITY & VOLENTEER SERVICE

Mechanical Designer GrabCAD Community Cambridge

JAN 2022- Present

Robotics Club DIURC Executive Member

Daffodil International University

PROJECT

NASA Challenge: New Transonic Wind Tunnel Test Section- Provided by NASA

Project: https://bit.ly/3qvp7k3

IMPLEMENTATION OF WIRELESS DATA, NUMBER AND TEXT SIGNAL

COMMUNICATION USING LI-FI TECHNOLOGY

Project: https://bit.ly/3CfRmG0

Smart Wheelchair

Project: https://bit.ly/3CfRzZO

Implementation of overload protection system

Project: https://bit.ly/3oDKRtL

Industrial Production Belt Controlling Project: https://bit.ly/43AYngg

RESEARCH PAPER

Islam, O., & Shikha, S. A. (2022). IoT application using a unique rectangular 2.4GHz microstrip patch antenna. arXiv. https://doi.org/10.48550/arXiv.2211.13096

Anny, F. T., & Islam, O. (2022). Sentiment analysis and opinion mining on Ecommerce site. arXiv. https://doi.org/10.48550/arXiv.2211.15536

REFERENCE

KANIJ AHMAD ASSISTANT PROFESSOR

DEPARTMENT OF ELECTRICAL AND ELECTRONIC ENGINEERING

DAFFODIL INTERNATIONAL UNIVERSITY

EMAIL: kanij.eee@diu.edu.bd WEB LINK; https://bit.ly/30QHdr5

MD. SOHEL RANA

SENIOR LECTURER

DEPARTMENT OF ELECTRICAL AND ELECTRONIC ENGINEERING

DAFFODIL INTERNATIONAL UNIVERSITY

EMAIL: sohel.eee@diu.edu.bd WEB LINK: https://bit.ly/3Pcawoj

LANGUAGE

- Bengali (Native) Fluent both speaking & Writing
- **English** Fluent both speaking & Writing
- Hindi Speaking

INTEREST





Reading Books



Learning **New Skills**



Photography

SOCIAL LINKS



ResearchGate



GrabCAD



Portfolio



LinkedIn



Google Scholar





HackerRank